const mcqs = [
    {
        "section": "A",
        "question": "The element having no neutron in the nucleus of its atom is",
        "options": ["Hydrogen", "Nitrogen", "Helium", "Boron"],
        "answer": "Hydrogen"
    },
    {
        "section": "A",
        "question": "The mass of cathode ray particle is :",
        "options": ["Same for different gases", "Different for different gases", "Minimum for H2 gas", "Different for same gases"],
        "answer": "Same for different gases"
    },
    {
        "section": "A",
        "question": "The ratio of the 'e/m' (specific charge) values of a electron and an α-particle is -",
        "options": ["2 : 1", "1 : 1", "1 : 2", "None of these"],
        "answer": "None of these"
    },
    {
        "section": "A",
        "question": "Rutherford's alpha particle scattering experiment eventually led to the conclusion that",
        "options": [
            "mass and energy are related",
            "electrons occupy space around the nucleus",
            "neutrons are buried deep in the nucleus",
            "the point of impact with matter can be precisely determined"
        ],
        "answer": "electrons occupy space around the nucleus"
    },
    {
        "section": "A",
        "question": "The fraction of volume occupied by the nucleus with respect to the total volume of an atom is",
        "options": ["10–15", "10–5", "10–30", "10–10"],
        "answer": "10–15"
    },
    {
        "section": "A",
        "question": "The approximate size of the nucleus of 64/28Ni is :",
        "options": ["3 fm", "4 fm", "5 fm", "2 fm"],
        "answer": "5 fm"
    },
    {
        "section": "B",
        "question": "The MRI (magnetic resonance imaging) body scanners used in hospitals operate with 400 MHz radio frequency. The wavelength corresponding to this radio frequency is:",
        "options": ["0.75 m", "0.75 cm", "1.5 m", "2 cm"],
        "answer": "0.75 m"
    },
    {
        "section": "B",
        "question": "Photon of which light has maximum energy :",
        "options": ["red", "blue", "violet", "green"],
        "answer": "violet"
    },
    {
        "section": "B",
        "question": "Electromagnetic radiations of wavelength 242 nm is just sufficient to ionize Sodium atom. Then the ionization energy of Sodium in kJ mole-1 is.",
        "options": ["494.65", "400", "247", "600"],
        "answer": "494.65"
    },
    {
        "section": "B",
        "question": "A bulb of 40 W is producing a light of wavelength 620 nm with 80% of efficiency then the number of photons emitted by the bulb in 20 seconds are (1eV = 1.6 × 10–19 J, hc = 12400 eV Å)",
        "options": ["2 × 1018", "1018", "1021", "2 × 1021"],
        "answer": "2 × 1021"
    }
]
export default mcqs;